<cafe id="paradigm-spark">
	<name>Paradigm Spark</name>
	<color>#4f890e</color>
	<summary>a glowing example of where single-minded devotion can take you</summary>
	<recc>pour-overs</recc>
	<write-up>
		i think Paradigm Spark is the best coffee in the city right now. They just took home 4th place at Canada's brewer's cup, so it's not hard to make the argument. 
	</write-up>
	<coords>51.03801877947663, -114.08253131921862</coords>
	<impression timestamp="2024-02-11">
		<coffee summary="3">
			<summary>a suite of well balanced beans. roasted in house.</summary>
			<write-up>
				the menu is split into a few categories of [beans, provided by david kim](https://www.davidkimcoffee.com/shop):

* sezita, the red one, with a classic third wave, red berry profile,
* duvixe, the blue one, with a your more pruney, chocolatey, blue berry, black tea kinda flavours,
* bohuma, the orange one, with developed stonefruit, dried fruit kinda flavours,
* kiyalo, the pink one, with more flowery, tropical fruit flavours.
			</write-up>
			<espresso summary="3">
				<summary>thick. juicy. intensely flavourful. hurts my teeth.</summary>
				<write-up>
					elegant and decadent. piercing, but in the way a hot young red wine is piercing: it allows the complexity to slowly unravel as it plays on the tongue.

					it balances the acid better than a lot of third wave places do, but when you get into the sezita line, things get hard. caveat emptor! consider a touch of oat milk!

					today i had the sezita and the kiyalo:
* the sezita is a burst of berry flavour: massive, looming. a classic flavour profile, and one of my favorite expressions of it.
* the kiyalo (Johan Vergara) is a bouquet with a backbone. massive floral flavour, with a beautiful, lactic richness. a lot less acidic than the sezita.
* the kiyalo (Milton Monroy) is a really neat burst of mangosteen.
				</write-up>
			</espresso>
			<short-drinks summary="3">
				<summary>gorgeous! bright, floral, rich, delicate. absurd variety.</summary>
				<write-up>
					i think there are currently 4 different beans available for espresso. of these, today, i had the kiyalo, my pour over favorite. it maintains all the rich, floral complexity of the pour over, but backs it up with a bit more power in the body.

					if there's one thing that's truly exceptional here, it's the texture they achieve in their macchiatos (the default short drink). the espresso on its own has a luxurious, thick, yet silky presence; the milk allows it to really coat the tongue. the foam is fluffy, warm, and cozy, holds it own in the mix, but doesn't distract from the main attraction. beautifully balanced.

					the espresso is—perhaps overly—acidic on its own, so i'd go with a macchiato ngl.
				</write-up>
			</short-drinks>
			<flights summary="3">
				<summary>there's a flight of 3 pour overs, and one espresso two ways</summary>
				<write-up>
					the beans used in the flights vary week to week, but they're always amazing. i recommend you sit at the bar and watch the whole process go down. there's a level of detail in the brewing you can't get elsewhere.
				</write-up>
			</flights>
			<pour-overs summary="3">
				<summary>highlight. get the flight.</summary>
				<write-up>
					i went to the thingdidoo with Josh, so i could easily write an essay here. i'll get around to it. until then:

					the level of technique on display is absurd. get the flight and sit at the bar.
				</write-up>
			</pour-overs>
			<variety summary="3">
				<summary> coffee list is [here](https://paradigmspark.com/pages/butterblock-cafe) </summary>
			</variety>
			<price>2</price>
		</coffee>
		<price summary="1"/>
		<food summary="2">
			<summary>good and great baked goods</summary>
			<write-up>this is the _Butter Block cafe_. Butter Blocks stuff runs from passable to pretty great, but not amazing.</write-up>
			<baked-goods summary="2"/>
		</food>
		<vibes summary="2">
			<summary>fairly standard 3rd wave vibes</summary>
			<write-up>
				apart from the rich, unique character of the devenish building the cafe is in, there isn't too much to say. the cafe is an extension of Butter Block's interior decoration.
			</write-up>
			<view summary="3">
				<summary>overlooks 17th</summary>
				<write-up>the cutest seating is next to the windows. </write-up>
			</view>
			<apollonian-aestheticism>3</apollonian-aestheticism>
			<involvement summary="3">
				<summary>it's easy to catch a love of coffee here</summary>
				<write-up>
					there's no better coffee bar in the city. the floor is very [open](https://youtu.be/UoCrx0scCkM?si=0sP5bYAHr2bWwvvr&amp;t=1336), with all the equipment and technique thusly scrutable.

					what you really need to do is talk. everyone is very friendly and extremely knowledgeable. ask about why all the coffee is pre-ground, why they only use the hario switch, why the bags of coffee are all different colours—anything that catches your eye. everything was chosen for a reason.
				</write-up>
			</involvement>
		</vibes>
		<other-bevvies summary="3">
			<summary>the original creations are all excellent</summary>
			<write-up>
				while the focus here is definitely coffee, i implore you to give the strawberry bombé a try. i think you'll be pleasantly surprised.
			</write-up>
			<hot-chocolate>3</hot-chocolate>
			<misc>3</misc>
			<variety>3</variety>
		</other-bevvies>
		<misc summary="0">
			<power>
					3
				<summary>basically all seating in the cafe has power</summary>
			</power>
		</misc>
	</impression>
</cafe>
