<root>
	<cafe id="european-bakery">
		<name>European Bakery</name>
		<color>#e83326</color>
		<coords>51.03766612184806, -114.07219196898996</coords>
    <summary>a bakery that serves surprisingly good turkish coffee</summary>
		<write-up>
			the European bakery is, foremostly, a eastern European bakery. they advertise the Turkish coffee on a small sign above the baked goods in the corner of the cafe. it's absolutely one of the best in downtown, and only about 3 dollars.

			all in all, this is a hidden gem, and the reason i made this website.
		</write-up>
		<impression timestamp="distant past">
			<coffee summary="2">
				<price>3</price>
				<turkish>
					2
				</turkish>
				<variety>1</variety>
			</coffee>
			<price summary="3">
				<baked-goods>3</baked-goods>
				<variety>3</variety>
			</price>
			<food summary="2">
				<summary>all manner of (mostly eastern) european baked goods and imports</summary>
				<write-up>
					the baked goods run the gamut from flat breads, northern european loaves, baguettes, and pretzels, to savory stuffed goods like [bureks](https://www.thespruceeats.com/traditional-yugoslavian-rolled-burek-borek-recipe-1805900). on the right side of the store are imports from all around Europe. everything is excellent and very reasonably priced.
				</write-up>
			</food>
			<vibes summary="2">
				<conversation>2</conversation>
			</vibes>
		</impression>
	</cafe>
	<cafe id="monogram">
		<name>Monogram</name>
		<color>#997600</color>
		<summary>what was the crown jewel of the calgary scene</summary>
		<recc>short-drinks</recc>
		<write-up>
			i don't have—a lot of—insider knowledge. but i pay close attention to some things when i go to cafes, especially when i go to the same cafe almost every day. Monogram was that for me. even [aubade](https://www.vancouvercoffeesnob.com/chinatown/aubade-coffee-2/) ran Monogram as their espresso.

			but things have been shifting. many things that i need to write a general "scene think piece" on that don't fit in this article, but also smaller things. the cortados went from being routinely excellent, to sometimes excellent, to always good. staff churn has been increasing. the seasonal drinks have all kinda sucked recently (including the hot chocolate fest hot chocolates).

			Monogram is still better than like, Deville or Analog or Phil and Sebastian, but the margin gets slimmer every year. It's all a bit depressing to think about.
		</write-up>
		<coords>51.049096124603615, -114.06718542186842</coords>
		<impression timestamp="2024-03-21">
			<coffee summary="2">
				<summary>Monogram is a no-mans-land between your 2s and your 3s</summary>
				<write-up>you should think of Monogram as quitessential third wave, calgary's revolver.</write-up>
				<short-drinks summary="2"><summary>very dependably good</summary></short-drinks>
				<pour-overs summary="2"><summary>chill. pretty standard.</summary></pour-overs>
				<variety summary="3"><summary>they run the standard gamut of coffee drinks, with little seasonal additions</summary></variety>
			</coffee>
		</impression>
	</cafe>
	<cafe id="t2722">
		<name>T2722</name>
		<color>#1077f3</color>
		<coords> 51.043029027997044, -114.03897643163158 </coords>
    <summary>genuinely world class. consider yourself fortunate we have access to this</summary>
		<write-up>
			we might think of T2722 as having three prongs: coffee, tea, and pastry. this is paralleled in the staff, 3 experts: Elle, Julian, and the mysterious french baker who i haven't spoken with. these three work 12 hour shifts, every day. the depths of their passion is a mystery even to me.

			the core idea is pairing these prongs. for each baked good, there's a matching tea or coffee drink. from each pairing emerges—at times—a truly sublime experience. i mean this very specifically and technically. it's like walking through a hallway that opens onto a cliff face, stumbling and flailing as you try not to fall [into a distractingly breath-taking vista](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zya8jdPa-rU). after that first time, every pairing placed before you is a mountain. the sublime seizes.

			T2722 started as a pop-up for hot chocolate fest in the Weslian hotel. they were easily the best hot chocolate that year, and have continued to levitate above the competition thence. for 2 years they've been doing pop-ups for some of the worlds biggest brands, and hosting tastings for some of the city's richest people. all ingredients are of a highest quality you can find in this city. it's definitely the priciest cafe on this list, but you can only get comparable quality in Tokyo or Paris for twice the price.
		</write-up>
		<impression timestamp="2024-02-18">
			<coffee summary="3">
				<summary>a principled, french approach to specialty</summary>
				<write-up>
					a facet is a window; the facet holds the gem up, and pours light into it, and sucks light out of it.

					to mill or grind coffee is not to facet it. coffee as such is not coffee itself. coffee is this other thing. when i talk about coffee, there's the taste, the aroma, the sight, the feel of the heat in your hands. there's the atmosphere, the thought you spare to the people you bring with you.

					there's the mouth feel, the heaviness, the comfort of coffee. as Paul Zits wrote, "day break[s]//under the coffee pot". T2722 captures this in a way i haven't felt since [aubade](https://www.vancouvercoffeesnob.com/chinatown/aubade-coffee-2/). it may not—it certainly doesn't—do high clarity the way other top tier coffeehouses do, but they do something special; something at the top of that game.

					please note that the variety is massive and constantly shifting, so i can't walk you through the experience of drinking what's currently on. just know that, with a bit of a conversation, you'll be able to find exactly what you want.
				</write-up>
				<americano summary="3">
					<summary>proper, hearty, heartwarming</summary>
				</americano>
				<price summary="2">
					<summary>strongly depends on what you're getting</summary>
					<write-up>on the other hand, i had something of a similar quality at [glitch](https://tokyocoffee.org/2016/04/15/glitch-coffee-roasters/) in Tokyo—admittedly in ochanomizu—for 4 times the price? so, again, reasonable.</write-up>
				</price>
				<short-drinks>3</short-drinks>
				<variety summary="3">
					<summary>genuinely absurd</summary>
					<write-up>
						the mind boggles. come in at a slow time and ask Julien for the list. then just ask him for a recommendation cuz it's all too much to take in.
					</write-up>
				</variety>
				<pour-overs summary="3">
					<summary>actually french presses</summary>
					<write-up>the french press gives body in a way that pour overs don't.</write-up>
				</pour-overs>
			</coffee>
			<price summary="1">
				<summary>but well worth it</summary>
			</price>
			<food summary="3">
				<summary>finally, [some good fucking food](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yWKeZe6ggJI)</summary>
				<write-up>
					i've had a lot of very good coffee. when i had the coffee here, it didn't blow my mind[1]. the food was genuinely life changing. i'm not certain why i've focused exclusively on beverages; why i've never sought out solid food this good before. i now feel this folly.

					i can't capture the actual experience, nor the techniques nor ingredients. i asked Julien how to categorize the dishes and he hasn't come up with the words yet, so i don't feel too bad.

					tldr; get in before they raise the price.

					[1] tbh, i'd never had a _really_ good medium-dark roast, so it did open my mind in that regard.
				</write-up>
				<baked-goods>3</baked-goods>
			</food>
			<vibes summary="3">
				<apollonian-aestheticism>3</apollonian-aestheticism>
			</vibes>
			<other-bevvies summary="3">
				<summary>While the emphasis is on coffee and tea, they have a few fascinating items at the back of the menu</summary>
				<write-up>
				</write-up>
				<tea summary="3">
				</tea>
				<hot-chocolate>3</hot-chocolate>
				<misc>3</misc>
				<variety>3</variety>
			</other-bevvies>
		</impression>
	</cafe>
	<cafe id="mobSquad">
		<name>MobSquad Cafe</name>
		<color>#9b54f3</color>
		<coords>51.04511335156388, -114.06521097396123</coords>
		<summary>excellent views</summary>
		<write-up>
			absolutely the best views in the city. if you can sneak in with a thermos of coffee from elsewhere, you've got the best of both worlds. inside, it feels like the decor was decided by an up and coming oil-sands failson with lots of capital and little taste.

			MobSquad cafe doubles as someone to marry to get a green card. 
		</write-up>
		<impression timestamp="distant past">
			<coffee summary="1">
				<short-drinks summary="1">
					<summary>genuinely the worst coffee i've had in years</summary>
					<write-up>bitter, acidic, sharp. mild petroleum note. primary notes include ash and dust. i wipe my brow and i slap my nuts. this is it, the apocalypse.</write-up>
				</short-drinks>
				<americano summary="1">
					<summary>the americano misto tasted like—nothing. whispers of ash and paper.</summary>
				</americano>
			</coffee>
			<price summary="2"></price>
			<vibes summary="2">
				<summary>get a window seat</summary>
				<write-up>
					the views are nice. i can see telus sky; the top of the bay building; the building Major Toms' is in; the head; &amp;c. i can see the trains and the people come and go, the cars stop and start and idle.

					inside is supposed to be some sort of co-working space, so there's plenty of seating. i've never seen this place more than 25% full. outlets are plentiful.

					as for the "vibe" proper: absolute airspace. a charmless corporate appropriation of third wave. it [transubstantiates](https://alexanderpruss.blogspot.com/2022/01/a-horizontal-aspect-to.html) the fairly standard [sirius xm coffee house](https://www.siriusxm.com/channels/the-coffee-house) bops into [pure bathos](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bathos).

					truly an edifying experience.
				</write-up>
				<view>3</view>
				<seating>3</seating>
			</vibes>
		</impression>
	</cafe>
	<cafe id="treno">
		<name>Treno</name>
		<color>#cc34cd</color>
		<coords> 51.04388902810284, -114.0717094825913 </coords>
    <summary> it's hard to think of something to say about Treno </summary>
		<write-up>my cat always used to say: &lt;q&gt;better to say nothing at all than something rude. focus on the positives!&lt;/q&gt;. to honour his cat-swag, i'll end the review here.</write-up>
		<impression timestamp="distant past">
			<coffee summary="1">
				<espresso>1</espresso>
			</coffee>
			<price summary="2"></price>
		</impression>
	</cafe>
</root>
